A Finding Aid to the Emily Hall Tremaine Papers, 1890-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.trememil
Archives of American Art
- Photographic Materials, 1890-1997; Series 8; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 8, 10-11
  Photographic materials are of Emily Hall Tremaine, her first husband, Maximilian von Romberg, and her second husband, Burton Tremaine, as well as two photo albums documenting works of art in the Tremaine collection. Photographs dating from Emily’s first marriage to von Romberg include photos of their friends and interiors of their residence, Brunninghausen. There are also photographs of the Tremaines' residences and Frank Lloyd Wright designs for a resort in Meteor Crater.
  Materials are arranged by subject and document type.
  - Album, von Romberg Residence, Brunninghausen, circa 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 2.
  - Albums, Tremaine Art Collection, circa 1950-1975 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Oversized materials housed in Box 11, Folder 1.
  - Photographs of Hall Family, 1890-1997 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Emily Hall, circa 1911 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Oversized materials housed in Box 11, Folder 2.
  - Photographs and Negatives of Emily Hall von Romberg, 1928-1939 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Emily Hall Spreckels, circa 1944 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Emily Hall Tremaine, circa 1945-1980 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Emily and Maximilian von Romberg, circa1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Oversized materials housed in Box 11, Folder 3.
  - Photographs of von Rombergs and Friends, circa 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    Oversized materials housed in Box 11, Folder 4.
  - Photographs of Maximilian von Romberg and Parents, circa 1895-1939 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Maximilian von Romberg, circa 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Photographs of von Romberg Residence, Brunninghausen, circa 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Negatives of von Romberg Residence, Brunninghausen, circa 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Contact Sheets and Negatives of Photos by von Romberg, circa 1990 (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
    Original photos taken in the 1930s.
  - Photographs and Negative of Portraits of the von Rombergs, circa 1930-1950 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Photograph and Negatives of Emily and Burton Tremaine, circa 1945-1980 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Burton Tremaine Sr., circa 1960-1970 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Negatives of Tremaine Residence, Madison and New York, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Negatives of Tremaine Resort, Meteor Crater, circa 1950-1990 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Oversized Album, von Romberg Residence from Box 8, Folder 20, circa 1930-1939 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Albums, Tremaine Art Collection from Box 8, Folder 21, circa 1950-1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Photographs of Emily Hall and Emily Hall von Romberg from Box 8, Folders 23-24, circa 1911-1939 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs of Emily and Maximilian von Romberg from Box 8, Folder 27, circa 1930-1939 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Photographs of Friends of von Rombergs and of Maximilian von Romberg from Box 8, Folders 28, 30, and 35, circa 1930-1939 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Includes photographs of portraits of Maximilian von Romberg.